hello friends welcome to the plugin
india channel this is the private india
electric vehicle issue tracker episode
number 11. this time we've got for you
ola electric a lot of ola scooters have
actually been delivered now and some of
them did have some issues so we're here
to document a couple of those issues
basically let me tell you quickly about
what issue tracker really is
issue tracker is a community focused
series where we bring out problems that
electric vehicle owners face whether
it's an eve three wheeler four-wheeler
or a larger wheeler
we want to document these issues for the
community at large if somebody else has
a similar issue they can probably find
the solution over here
this is not affirmative like whatsapp
where it's on your message and away this
is going to be permanent it's going to
stay on our forums so even much later if
somebody searches they can find these
issues and possible solutions this is
also a place for you to help out your
fellow eevee owners where if you found
an issue and solved it you can document
it over here so that other people may
take advantage we also try our best
using our contacts in the ev industry to
help out people who have these issues so
if you do document your issue over here
we will try our best to get your
favorable solution
having said that let's jump right in
we've got three interesting issues for
you on the ola s1 pro
[Music]
so our first issue is with an ola s1 pro
where the display comes off while riding
the scooter itself
this happened to mr heisenberg on the
23rd of jan 2022 and he was riding
between the belgaewa highway at around 6
pm when suddenly his display count off
there is a video that we've given
which you can see what actually happened
to him and uh in order to fix this
problem he kind of took his scooter to
the side of the road near a petrol bump
bunk so he could kind of figure out what
the problem was and after a couple of
seconds the scooter actually turned off
and locked the handle and he couldn't
ride at all he was absolutely stranded
unfortunately for him it started raining
and it was quite cold at 10 or 20
degrees where he did not have protective
clothing so this exacerbated the problem
for him so he had a few minor issues and
the vehicle was going to be taken in
two service in two or three days anyway
but because of this they had to arrange
a pickup immediately he spoke to ola
support he told him that they don't have
any way to remotely lock and lock the
scooter and that it would have to be got
in using the roadside assistance so
around 10 30 roads and assistance came
in after about four grueling hours in
the cold which was i feel the really bad
part
uh however after the scooter got taken
in they fixed the problem because it was
a loose connector and he says in his
comment below that
there is a connector which is right
below the headlight and this was a
little bit loose while assembling the
scooter and he just snapped and they
would have probably snapped it in and
the display would start to work again
this kind of brings to mind guys that
you we should probably have some kind of
a toolkit when we ride our vehicles for
these simple diy fixes that we can do
the technician could probably guide us
over the phone and we could ourselves uh
fix the problem by opening a screw nuts
boards going a little bit in and fixing
the wire luckily for him this wasn't a
season issue with any other part but yes
the discomfort of not of staying out in
the cold for four and a half hours would
certainly be something that one wouldn't
want so this is an issue which is now
resolved uh a simple connector being
loose so thank you eisenberg for sharing
this other people will also know that if
in case they do have this similar
problem this is how it can be fixed
[Music]
so guys here we have another issue which
is a very common issue that has been
reported to us by the ola owners club
and this is when the forward and reverse
mode of the ola electric scooter gets
reversed there's a video available which
we have put up for you to see uh you can
see that here is an owner who is
actually
putting the accelerator forward he is
squeezing the accelerator uh in a
forward direction and the scooter seems
to be going backward then he switches
the mode to reverse and he is
squeezing the absolute in the opposite
direction because it seems that's how
you're going to reverse enola and the
scooter is going forward so this is a
common problem that has been reported
and let's see what uh has been told to
this person by the ola team there's a
comment by mr abhijit who said that it's
just a guess but he's saying that people
seem to be wanting to have some kind of
a cruise control and there's a combo
button which they use and if they use
this too often somehow it gets stuck in
the vehicle's memory and when you start
the scooter without showing reverse it's
actually in reverse mode
another thing that he says that if there
are kids who are playing with the
accelerator it kind of sometimes gets
stuck in full throttle mode and this
could also be a problem this uh issue
was brought up by plugin india team to
the ola electric team and they have
responded with the following message it
says the issue has been passed on to the
engineering service team so the person
who has
sent the original video
was has been responded to by the ola
team and the maharashtra and goa team
has called him up and spoken to him
directly so we have a message now from
he says that
hi the scooter shown in the video is
mine and i took the video just a few
minutes ago received a call from ola
regional service head and he said that
all issues will be fixed soon and they
are a priority he also told me that i
have any issue here after i can directly
contact him it really boosts my
confidence in the company well that's
really good to know folks uh let's see
what mithesh says once he gets his bug
fix here is another video from mr one
guy who has posted this video on twitter
it's about his ola s1 pro and you can
see what happens to his scooter when he
tries moving it unfortunately he seems
to bang into the wall and fall down as
well finally we have a comment from
recently updated us so mithesh has just
updated us that the ola team from
bangalore has visited him and updated
the software possibly his bug is now
fixed but we are waiting on nitesh to
get back to us after his testing and let
us know if the problem is indeed solved
so as far as i'm concerned i feel that
there are some code paths with which the
scooter software gets into which are
causing these bugs and ola should
definitely invest more time energy
effort and make sure that every possible
alternative of the flow chart and every
code is written so that such bugs don't
come up because these can really be
serious issues and other than that ola
is definitely taking action they are
putting these things on priority and
trying to solve these problems and let's
see what users for the report so thank
you mithesh and thank you much for
reporting your problems
please keep us surprised of the progress
and final solution if your problem has
completely been solved
[Music]
so the final issue that we have is range
suddenly dropping to zero a lot of ola
s1 pro users have reported this and here
is a video from mr sumit and which shows
this problem actually happening you can
see that he's got
about 50 kilometers of range left it's a
little bit shaky but if you pay
attention and then he rotates the video
but you can still take a look on the
bottom left and you can see that at 35
40 40 kilometers suddenly his range
drops to zero kilometers so this is
definitely a problem you can't have your
scooter doing this to you
ola has reportedly had these issues and
replaced the entire pack for the owner
which in a way i feel is a great thing
because they are saving the owner from
the hassle of going through the repair
process but we also feel that they
should build some local capability so
that somebody can come and fix the issue
or repair the issue at a local level so
having said that i would just like to
say that at plug in india we believe in
repair and feel that it is much more
eco-friendly than having replacement or
even recycling because the materials are
continually being used however i think
replacing the pack for the owner
directly means less hassle for them they
can go on their own and then hola itself
can repair the refurbisher facts and use
them in some other way so we also have
mr mitesh who has reported the same
problem he has contacted ola and they
have replaced the pack for him and we
are waiting for further feedback from
him to let you know if this has indeed
fixed his problem
so thank you guys for sharing the
problems with us and letting the
community know what's going on and how
the problems can be solved if you have
any comments feedback please write in
the comments below and let us know if
you have problems that you want
solutions to put them here if you have
found a solution to your problem please
put that also over here as an added
comment i think ola has done a fantastic
job of setting up the future factory
delivering these amazing products with
fantastic specifications fully connected
to evs and now we wish that in order to
maintain this legacy in or to continue
offering such fantastic product they
need to keep service at priority one
they need to make sure that they are
delivering on their promise home
deliveries home service and making sure
that customer has least amount of bother
and hassle
[Music]
you